🗷 ruidantas55@gmail.com 📞 6472378213 👂 Toronto, Ontario 🛮 in Rui Dantas 👩 Ruheee

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with a passion for Front-end Development. Through my years of working as a self-taught freelance Creative Director, Photographer/Videographer, and Graphic designer in the music industry, I was able to build the work ethic, problem-solving skills, and teamwork skills needed to strive in such industries and come out with happy and satisfied clients. Through a strong process of research, planning, design, development, and testing, I am able to create fully functioning web application that meets the needs of clients.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, SQL

FRAMEWORK & LIBRARIES: NodeJS, React, Ajax, Express, EJS, jQuery, Rails

SYSTEMS & DATABASES: PostgreSQL, Git

TESTING: Jest, Storybook, Cypress

GRAPHIC DESIGN: Photoshop, Illustrator, Lightroom

PROJECTS

Tweeter · Nov. 2022

Tweeter is a simple, single-page Twitter clone.

- Frontend: Javascript, jQuery, AJAX

- Backend: Express, NodeJs

Card-Heroes · Feb. 2023

Card Heroes is the ultimate destination for trading card enthusiasts. With over a million cards to choose from, we have the perfect card for every collector.

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, JS, EJS, SASS

- Backend: Node, Express, PostgreSQL

Scheduler · Mar. 2023

React-based project to create meetings for students to connect with mentors in real time.

- Frontend: React, Axios, Classnames, Normalize, Storybook

TinyAPP · Nov. 2022

RESTful URL Shortening service.
- Backend: Express, Node

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs · Oct. 2022 to May 2023

Diploma Full-Stack Web Development

Chaminade College School · Sept. 2012 to June 2016

High-School Diploma 2016

EMPLOYMENT

Freelance Photographer/Videographer

Creative Director - Sept. 2016 to Current - Los Angeles, California/ Toronto, Ontario

- Develop and execute creative vision: As a creative director, My primary responsibility is to develop and execute the creative vision for an Artist. This involves working closely with the musician to understand their goals and objectives and then developing a strategy for achieving those goals through innovative and compelling creative content.
- Lead and manage a small team of creative individuals: This includes providing direction, feedback, and guidance on creative projects, as well as ensuring that all work is completed on time and within budget.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams: I was responsible for ensuring that all creative content aligned with the overall brand and messaging by collaborating with graphic designers, videographers, stylists, etc. We worked together to ensure that our vision supports the goals and objectives of the artist.

Photographer / Videographer & Graphic Designer - Apr. 2017 to Current - Los Angeles, California/ Toronto, Ontario

- Capture and edit visual content: As a photographer/videographer & designer, my primary role is to capture and edit visual content, including photos, videos, and graphics, for use in various mediums such as websites, social media, and marketing materials.
- Collaborate with clients: I was responsible for collaborating with clients to understand their vision and goals, and then developing a strategy for capturing and creating visual content that aligns with the overall vision and that it supports the goals and objectives of the artist.
- Design and produce marketing materials: In addition to visual content creation, I was also responsible for designing and producing marketing materials, such as flyers, press kits, and other promotional materials. This includes selecting and editing visual content, as well as creating layout and design elements that effectively convey the client's message and brand identity.